const quizQuestions = [
    {
        path: "Frontend",
        questions :[
            {
                question: "Which of the following is used to style the appearance of a website?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "HTML"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "CSS"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "JavaScript"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "Python"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "B"
            },
            {
                question: "What is the main programming language used for creating the structure and content of a webpage?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "HTML"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "CSS"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "JavaScript"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "PHP"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "A"
            },
            {
                question: "Which of the following is responsible for adding interactivity to a website?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "HTML"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "CSS"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "JavaScript"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "Ruby"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "C"
            },
            {
                question: "Which HTML tag is used to define the main heading of a webpage?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "<header>"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "<h1>"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "<title>"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "<main>"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "B"
            },
            {
                question: "Which CSS property is used to change the color of text?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: " font-size"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "text-align"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "color"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "background-color"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "C"
            },
            
        ]
    },

    {
        path: "Backend",
        questions :[
            {
                question: "Which JavaScript runtime environment is commonly used for backend development?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "Node.js"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "React"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "Angular"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "Vue.js"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "Node.js"
            },
            {
                question: "Which module in Node.js is used to handle file operations?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "http"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "fs"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "path"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "express"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "B"
            },
            {
                question: "Which command is used to install external libraries or packages in Node.js?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "npm install"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "node install"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "package install"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "npm start"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "A"
            },
            {
                question: "Which of the following modules in Node.js is used for creating web servers?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "http"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "fs"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "net"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "os"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "A"
            },
            {
                question: "Which method is commonly used in Node.js to handle asynchronous operations?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "setTimeout()"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "setInterval()"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "async-await"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "for loop"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "C"
            },
        ]
    },

    {
        path: "Web3",
        questions :[
            {
                question: "What does Web3 refer to in the context of the internet?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "The third version of the World Wide Web"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "A new programming language for web development"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "A decentralized internet powered by blockchain technology"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "An online marketplace for buying and selling goods"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "C"
            },
            {
                question: "Which technology is commonly associated with Web3 applications?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "Artificial Intelligence (AI)"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "Virtual Reality (VR)"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "Blockchain"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "Internet of Things (IoT)"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "C"
            },
            {
                question: "What is the primary advantage of Web3 technology?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "Faster internet speeds"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "Enhanced online security and privacy"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "Improved website design and user experience"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "Access to a larger selection of online games"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "B"
            },
            {
                question: "Which cryptocurrency is often used in Web3 applications?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "Bitcoin"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "Ethereum"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "Ripple"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "Litecoin"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "B"
            },
            {
                question: "What is a smart contract in the context of Web3 technology?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "An agreement between two parties that is automatically enforced by a computer program"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "A code snippet used for web development in JavaScript"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "A virtual reality simulation accessed through a web browser"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "A new type of search engine that uses machine learning algorithms"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "A"
            },
            
        ]
    },

    {
        path: "Product Design",
        questions :[
            {
                question: "What does UI stand for in product design?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "User Information"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "User Interaction"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "User Interface"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "User Involvement"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "C"
            },
            {
                question: "What does UX stand for in product design?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "User Experience"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "User Expertise"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "User Expansion"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "User Exclusion"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "A"
            },
            {
                question: "What is the primary goal of UI design?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "To make a product visually appealing"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "To ensure the product is easy to use and navigate"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "To create a strong marketing strategy"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "To optimize the product for search engines"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "A"
            },
            {
                question: "What is the primary goal of UX design?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "To create an intuitive and satisfying user experience"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "To choose the right color palette for the product"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "To optimize the product for mobile devices"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "To design attractive icons and graphics"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "A"
            },
            {
                question: "Which of the following is NOT typically involved in the UX design process?",
                options: [
                    {
                        value: "A",
                        option: "User research and analysis"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "B",
                        option: "Wireframing and prototyping"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "C",
                        option: "Graphic design and visual aesthetics"
                    },
                    {
                        value: "D",
                        option: "Usability testing and iteration"
                    },
                ],
                correctOption : "C"
            },
            
        ]
    }
]

export default quizQuestions